STEPHANIE HONORE

Senior Software Engineer | M.S. Computer Science

+1(423) 321-9096 @ stephanie.honore@proton.me http://www.smhonore.com

Austin, TX

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Alaska Airlines 07/2022 - Present Austin, TX (Remote)

- Working with agile scrum team to do rapid iteration, feature-driven, frontend & backend coding and E2E testing for flight search modernization initiative for ecommerce web app. (https://www.alaskaair.com/search).
- Creating unit tests with adequate code coverage, practicing DevSecOps through creation of automated testing, deployment & vulnerability scanning in CI/CD pipeline.
- Working with cloud platform for CDN, static web apps, log analysis, APIM, Kubernetes/docker. Working with digital experience analytics for RUM, user interaction heat map analysis, and conversion rate tracking.
- Assisting with maintenance of Auro open-source design system (https://auro.alaskaair.com/#gsc.tab=0).
- Vice chair of the Women in Technology employee resource group and member of the Machine learning guild and privacy & security guild.

Software Engineer

Keller Williams Realty, Inc 07/2021 - 06/2022 Austin, TX (Hybrid) International real estate company

- Working with MLS listing data for adding new features and bug remediation on Keller Williams's consumer-facing platform kw.com and KW mobile app.
- . Collaborating with offshore team on KW Worldwide initiative to perform localization for international markets
- Full-stack software development, creating unit tests, doing smoke tests, and cloud development
- Mentoring associate engineers and peers with problem-solving and knowledge sharing to improve overall team productivity. Interviewing candidate for individual contributor position
- Assisting Senior Director and VP with product research, discovery calls with vendors and generating evaluation reports. Overseeing the procurement of new tools to use within the enterprise
- Growing companies Black ERG from the ground up with small team to kick-started DEL initiatives within the company
- · Assisting cybersecurity team with information security and data governance

Lead Software Engineer

Deloitte 09/2020 - 07/2021 Austin, TX (Remote)

Advisory and consulting firm to government and public sector - Discovery and Disclosure

- Founding member of a small scrum team working on greenfield e-discovery project for modernizing an e-discovery web app that integrated with 3rd party vendors such as Relativity, NUIX, and IPRO from Microsoft silverlight to a modern tech stack.
- Frontend and backend software development with React & .NET Core
- Introduced UI prototyping and automated deployment pipeline to team
 Worked on the design and frontend implementation of gov cloud hosted file upload application
- Wrote SQL queries using triggers, aggregate functions, stored procedures, table indexes, profiling, and table-valued function
- Remediated bugs in Relativity concerning batches (a collection of documents) in the review workflow and document search
- · Testing with Jest and JUnit.

Senior Software Engineer (Deloitte Contractor)

CSI Technologies 01/2020 - 08/2020 Austin, TX (On-site)
Contracting agency

- Founding member of a small scrum team working on greenfield e-discovery project for modernizing an e-discovery web app that integrated with 3rd party vendors such as Relativity, NUIX, and IPRO from Microsoft silverlight to a modern tech stack.
 Building web app with React and .NET Core that integrated with 3rd party vendors such as Relativity, NUIX, and IPRO
- · Introduced unit tests, code formatting, and linting to team
- Writing queries with SQL Server Management Studio

ABOUT ME

Having worked in the tech industry for seven years, I have gained in-depth knowledge and experience that enables me to deliver quality software solutions that are practical, maintainable and add value to your organization. I am a continuous learner who is interested in exploring new coding languages, libraries and frameworks. I also am focusing on developing effective communication strategies and gaining leadership skills to help advance my career.

FIND ME ONLINE

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/smhonore

GitHub Personnal www.github.com/shonore

GitHub Professional www.github.com/shonore-aa

YouTube https://www.youtube.com/@smhonore

EDUCATION

International Security Graduate Certificate

Harvard Extension School 01/2023 - Present

M.S. Computer Science - Data Science Concentration

The University of Tennessee at Chattanooga 08/2015 - 12/2018

B.S. Animal Science University of Tennessee 08/2010 - 05/2014

FAVORITE ACHIEVEMENT

Optimizing Address Searches

Taking a concept from a stakeholder's idea to a full-stack deliverable in a timely manner that had improved the search capabilities for our guest by reducing the overall search refinement rate by providing more relevant and accurate results in the initial search. This involved Researching the search index feature in MongoDB Atlas and working with the team software architect to implement a solution for optimizing text searches to recognize full property addresses searches using geolocation instead of doing a partial match on a single field in our address database. You can see the results in the search bar on https://kw.com/.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Software Engineer

Usio, Inc 08/2019 - 01/2020 Austin, TX (On-site)

Payment processing & prepaid card solutions

- React Native and Angular frontend software development who collaborated with backend development team to create client-consumable responses for the Akimbo cross-platform mobile app and the Akimbo web app (https://usio.com/cardissuing/).
- · Working on bugs for white labeled apps
- . Introducing Scrum Agile methodologies to the software development team (Sprint planning, sprint reviews, and retrospectives)
- · Writing automated e2e tests using Screwdriver
- · Eliciting and documenting business requirements in flow diagram

Frontend Software Engineer

Unum 12/2018 - 07/2019 Chattanooga, TN (On-site)

Disability and leave insurance provider

- Front end development using React to build mobile responsive web app from UX designs on agile scrum team
- Creating unit tests with 80% code coverage
- · Version control (trunk-based development) and CI/CD processes
- Building FAQ website with knowledge center on Salesforce and Kentico headless CMS
- Leading Daily Stand Ups, Retrospectives and Sprint planning ceremonies
- Researched 3 different NLP chatbot options and how they would integrate with call center platform for ticketing and agent response.

Application Developer

BlueCross BlueShield of Tennessee 08/2017 - 12/2018

Chattanooga, TN (On-site)

Health insurance company

- Elicited business requirements from stakeholders and created well-defined epics, features, and user stories with functional requirements
- Project management for small to medium-sized projects (less than 500 hours) using Project Portfolio Management tool. Cleaned up project area and generated reports for leaders in the director level and above.
- Managing 2 product backlogs with lead product owner. Completed cleared an entire backlog.
- Leading backlog prioritization meetings with key stakeholders and leadership for determining product roadmap for team
- · Mentored 2 interns and a jr business analyst
- · Front-end software development
- Improving entity relationship diagrams for generating business logic from SQL queries for user stories

Intern

BlueCross BlueShield of Tennessee 03/2017 - 08/2017

Chattanooga, TN (On-site)

Health insurance company

- . Facilitated and lead agile scrum ceremony meetings such as sprint refinement, sprint planning, and daily stand up
- Elicited business requirements from stakeholders and created well-defined user stories with functional requirements
- · Front-end Application development for internal web app
- Working with QA team for developing test cases and doing manual quality assurance
- · Assisted with vetting legacy user stories and combining 2 product backlogs into one
- . Learning healthcare provider entity relationship diagrams for generating business logic from SQL queries for user stories
- · Creating and maintaining team documentation

Intern

CodeScience 01/2016 - 10/2016 Chattanooga, TN (Hybrid)

Consulting and services company that specializes in helping businesses build and launch software applications on the Salesforce platform

- Planned and kicked-off a small project for creating an app on Salesforce's Force.com platform using declarative and programmatic approach. Coordinated with 2 Jr
- Using whiteboarding technique to create flow diagrams for documenting business logic. Came up with a solution to use standard deviation to classify alerts.
- Conducted UX design research and created wireframes and mockups using Sketch
- Generating Salesforce marketing research report using Google Analytics and HubSpot

SIDE PROJECTS

Fluffyhead Goods

01/2022 - Present Austin, TX

Creating an e-commerce coffee business from the ground up. Creating branding, designing the graphics, conducting customer research, sourcing the product, setting up the website, and doing digital marketing & advertising

https://fluffyheadgoods.com/

Fickle iOS & Android Mobile App

06/2021 - Present Austin, TX

Working on a cross-platform mobile app using React Native, NodeJS, and GraphQL.

http://www.fickleapp.com/

CERTIFICATION

React Certificate

HackerRank

JavaScript (Basic) Certificate -

HackerRank

Communication Skills for Professionals

University of Texas Austin Center for Professional Education (CPE)

TRAINING / COURSES

Cyber Incident Response - Coursera

International Cyber Conflicts - Coursera

IT Security: Key Policies and Resources - LinkedIn

SKILLS

Javascript • React.JS • Tensorflow • Python (learning) •

PyTorch (learning) • Juypter Notebook (learning) •

AWS S3 . AWS Lambda . Azure Static Web App .

product management • project management •

Azure Frontdoor • Unit test • e2e testing •

Object-Oriented Design • BFF pattern •

microservice architecture •

Service-oriented architecture • business analysis •

React Native . Svelte . . NET Core . CSS . HTML .

Cypress • GraphQL • Apollo • cybersecurity •

JavaScript • Jest • NodeJS • C# • Git • SQL •

MongoDB Atlas • SQL Management Studio • Scrum •

Software Development • Unit Testing •

Feature-flag development • Figma • Azure •

Amazon Web Services . Google Cloud Platform .

Docker • Kubernetes • Snyk • Typescript • Optimizely • Launch Darkly •